Yeah, I'm here, yeah.
OK. OK. Thank you. Um
OK,
you you said this is the tender summary.
This is what I thought.
This was the tender summary for this part,
I don't see your screen.
but you.
Sorry.
And.
I think I'm sharing it. Oh, now. OK,
now it's.
Yeah.
So you were telling me this is not a
summary, right? The tender tap for?
This is not a summary,
it is just the if you go to yeah next
screen page 4.
H4.
Yeah, it's just, yeah,
it is just the top view.
The top view.
The top view is not fully showing. Yeah,
yeah, just those blocks.
Oh, so.
It is just showing a little bit because
it's not a full screen view.
Oh.
OK,
so this is this is the same thing as this,
right?
Yeah.
Oh no.
Yeah, it is the same thing as that.
It's just the view is like halfway.
Like large, Yeah. OK.
So everything in tender inside monitoring
Yeah.
is this basically, right?
Yeah, yeah.
And inside that you have this this this
options as well, right?
Oh my gosh. So this is big. Like,
that's why you call it tender,
Yeah.
because it's only about tender.
Yeah, yeah,
it's only about tender and that same
thing you need to replicate in the first
tab as well, the exceptions, right?
See for example,
it is automatically tendering when it is
in monitoring.
I told you it automatically does the
system, does the tendering, right?
But there are some interventions.
Huh.
That the user would have to make a call,
right?
Mhm.
Say for example in the case like how do
you say there were like something related
to the date, it cannot decide.
If I if the system can automatically
tender to one of the option,
I call the option as a carrier, right?
So if it is not able to decide if it can
tender to the next carrier,
it'll move the shipment from this
monitoring screen into the exception
screen. So your screen.
Yeah, he all got back.
Yeah,
it'll go back where the user will have to
resolve.
So that is why I'm saying the standard
screen is common between the exception
box and the monitoring box, right?
It is just that the status inside it will
be different.
It started as if you go to page four or
five, right?
Right. The status inside it.
Here it says sent.
There it'll be saying something else
review or something, you know it declined,
right?
It'll show us tender decline and then
it'll go here.
To the exception box.
The exception box and.
Yeah, shipment exception box.
If you see the tender status,
tender status is sent here, right?
If you will look at the 5th column in the
table.
The first column in the table. Yes, this,
this.
5th, 5th, 5th, 5th, 5th column,
not the first fifth tender status
OK.
1234567th column. Yeah,
tender status you see? Yeah,
And.
there it is sent. If it is sent,
there are a couple of other statuses,
This one.
right? If it is sent.
Then if it is being, if it is done,
if it is like right,
Mhm.
let's take two statuses, right?
Send done right then in those statuses
So.
it'll be in monitoring,
but if it is declined, if it is cancelled.
Right there is the system needs doesn't
know what to do for the next tender.
It'll come to monitoring because it
requires a user action.
That is why I'm saying screen wise it'll
be same status inside it will be
different.
Now I understand this. OK, yeah,
this was a big misunderstanding then. OK,
now I understand.
But one question you don't need to.
You don't need to show everything inside
tender like this when we are in in in
exceptions, right?
You need to show everything on inside the
tender because they might want to see it,
right? Right.
Say what happens inside the tender.
But sometimes, yeah, it is the same thing.
Yeah, yeah.
Hmm. OK, so it's the same thing.
It's the same thing for OK.
Content wise is the same thing. OK.
The content rights, it is the same thing.
That's what I'm saying.
It's only the status that is going to
change. You don't don't put it as sent,
keep it as canceled or decline or
something so that the user would have to
review when you keep it in the first box.
But if it is in the monitoring,
it is just monitoring.
You're not going to take any action,
right? And as you see here.
Mhm.
Here on the top it is on hold. It is on.
It is send.
Hold means don't put any tender status.
It is just hold, right?
The tender has not started, right?
It is just waiting for the right time to
start the tender, right? So consolidation,
it's like just to say that there is a
separate. Don't worry,
forget about consolidation for you.
It is not important,
but I know what technically what needs to
be done under consolidation.
You just show what you show the same data
under consolidations as well, right?
Hold and consolidations. Forget about it.
OK.
Just keep different shipments.
That's all right.
Send this the tender status.
One of the line in the option is sent.
Don't put multiple send.
There can be only one.
Sent at a time, one option is sent, right?
Yeah, 111 cent per order, right? It was,
I think, no.
Yeah, options. I call these as options.
You see carrier name SCAC.
Each one is a different SCAC.
It is like you're generating a list of
carriers to whom you would want to go and
review the tender with.
Mm-hmm. OK, I see. Um.
Right.
You have a shipment.
It is like you have a shipment,
then you get rates from different people,
right? You go FedEx,
Huh.
you go then to UPS or your local Courier
guy and get all the rates and then
whenever you get start.
You know where you get all the rates and
you don't know who is going to accept it,
right?
Because the system is like you send the
information one by one.
You send first send to FedEx guy and
you're waiting for the response.
He might accept it or he might not accept
it. If he accepts it,
it'll be sent and then the tender is done.
Right,
because he has accepted it and you have
finalized the carrier.
But imagine the FedEx guy did not accept
it.
Then you have next in the list to send it
to the UPS guy, right?
The UPS would be then look taking care of,
Uh huh.
you know he will do the same thing.
He will review it and give a response.
If he accepts it, that's it.
Now I fix the carrier to be UPS.
If he did not do it,
then you'll go to the third carrier.
So that is where the rank helps you.
The rank 123 on the second column tells
you how you need to go do it right.
Mhm.
You need to 1st send it to rank one that
is AAA Cooper.
Then you need to send it to rank 2,
which is SIAM order, right?
You need to send the tender to them.
You have to wait for the response.
Then if you send if the information is
passed from Odyssey's end to AAA Cooper,
it is called the sent message.
Right. They can accept it or decline.
When they decline it,
it comes back to you and say you need to
find a different carrier because the
carrier does not want to move your
shipment and then immediately you would
send it to Saya.
OK.
So it one by one you evaluate and you
wait for whether the sire is going to
accept it or not.
So that is why I'm saying when system is
automatically doing,
I see.
it'll be in the monitoring phase, right?
Planning, monitoring.
Sure.
But if the system doesn't know to do it
by itself,
it'll be in planning exception where the
user would have to review and.
Yeah, review and resolve it.
Which is this one?
That is why I was, yeah,
that is what I was saying.
Both the screens are same,
it's just the small details inside it is
different.
I know I understand now and for for the
for the monitoring difference because in
Yeah.
monitoring you use you mentioned a
difference from here between a difference
that here we have.
From the the exceptions, right?
Which was this part, right?
Correct, correct.
The tender status. OK,
right now the tender status in our design
and let me let me go to there in there in
order. Oh, sorry.
Inner design is.
It like this.
Correct. Yeah, you have it as rejected,
rejected, accepted, right?
It's like this, right?
Uh huh.
Right, that needs to be changed.
This design needs to be changed to the
design that you have on the PPT.
OK, OK. And what's the difference?
Can you repeat that?
What's the difference between that design
for monitoring and the design for
exceptions? Which part of the?
Both are same. This is how it needs to be.
Whatever you see on the screen, right?
The PPT, that's how it needs to be.
That's why I'm saying that design wise
it's no change.
Design wise it's the same between
monitoring and exceptions.
But what you have for monitoring should
Mm OK.
not be the one that you have right now.
It should be like the one that you have
in the PPT.
Oh, OK, OK, I got you. Got you.
So because what I was thinking is that
since we are doing exceptions here,
we're taking actions, right?
But since we are monitoring here,
we are just seeing.
Like like monitoring, right? Uh.
Yeah, monitoring. No actions required.
It's just to monitor to someone wants to
see which is being currently tendered to
or who it is being tendered to, right.
They can come and see, OK,
it is now it's AAA Cooper. OK,
Oh.
then that's all.
That's all they would know, right?
They would want to.
They won't take any actions here.
Mostly they will take actions in the
first box.
Um.
That is why I'm saying the screen wise it
is all the same,
but what action they would take and do is
all going to be dependent on the first
screen because it's it's the user action
that is required.
B.
Because right now in the exceptions we
have this this box that let us change it
between between different carriers.
Correct.
OK,
and the other one will not have this
right despite we have this in in your
design.
Yeah, yeah, it's it'll still be there.
It'll still be there, right? See,
Uh.
say for example, if they,
if it is being sent,
say let's take in monitoring as well.
Suddenly someone says the customer says
Mhm.
that, you know, cancel that shipment,
I'm not going to ship,
then you should have an action.
To cancel the sent, right,
you have to say cancel the shipment,
cancel the tender.
So you are canceling it.
But when the carrier says no,
I cannot do it, that is a decline.
So there is a different terminology,
you see that.
So when you cancel because a customer
does not want the shipment to be moved.
They can come here to the monitoring and
then do the cancellation right.
It is still required.
Actions are still required,
but what they are going to act will be
different.
You.
That's why I'm saying forget because
OK.
these are all more business rules and all
those things, right?
It'll be too much for you.
What I'm trying to tell you is just
replicate the same screen between
monitoring as well As for exceptions.
So you're if you go back to your screen,
if you go back to your design.
Mhm.
Hmm.
Right,
so the tender should look exactly like
the PPT.
Mm-hmm. Yes,
right now this doesn't make sense.
If if we compare it,
it's like too simplistic, right?
Too simplistic.
The status is only thing that will change.
Mm.
The tender status is the only thing that
will change.
I'll tell you later if there is anything
that you need to do here,
Yeah.
you will not have accepted when you are
in monitoring.
Sorry in you when you are in.
The right exceptions you will not have
accepted.
You will have cancelled or declined.
That's it. Declined. It's not rejected,
it's declined.
It's either cancelled or declined, right?
That's how you will have it.
Right you they you will never have
accepted in a exception.
Only in monitoring you can have sent or
accepted.
Oh,
and monitoring you will have only sent
and accepted. OK, perfect.
And the and you you gave me a correction
Correct, correct.
here as well because here for example we
have sent, declined,
rejected and there is other that is
cancelled that is not showing in my right
Mhm.
now in my.
Like in my example,
but I know that in the in the in my
Yeah.
database exists, accepted, declined,
rejected and cancelled. Is that OK? OK,
Yeah, correct. Yeah.
OK, good.
Oh.
You have you have sent.
There is uh little one will be sent right?
Yeah, that is.
That is the one that I have as well.
Yeah.
Here is. I think I'll show you one. Yeah,
let me let me search for one.
Here it is sent.
Sent. Correct. Sent.
Then I believe next is accepted and
declined.
Let me see that I let me show you.
Maybe that'll be easy for you.
There are so many statuses that you might
not need.
That's why I'm saying these are all going
to be.
Technical thing, right?
So when I write the rules,
I will write it,
but you don't need it when you show the
design,
you just need one or two statuses just to
show them so that the the business folks
understand.
Mm-hmm. OK.
Right. And you don't.
You don't have to spend your time doing
all that.
That's why I was trying to tell you.
Let me see. Let me take. Yeah, OK,
these are all the status.
OK.
Let me share my screen quick.
Mhm.
Are you able to see my screen?
Yeah.
OK, this is how it'll be, right?
These are tender rights.
OK.
There's a lot of information for you.
You don't need it. That's what I'm saying.
Hmm.
These are shipment statuses. You see here,
it'll start from hold. It'll go to review,
right? From review, it can go to approved.
From approved it can go to load board,
load board to spot bid,
bid review from it goes to done right.
From done it can go back to review
because the carrier dropped it or carrier
said that he cannot do it.
So it can go to review right and then
it'll go through all these statuses.
Um.
This is shipment status.
If you take tender status,
tender status is accepted, cancelled,
to be cancelled, cancel, fail, decline,
decline, fail, sent, skipped, empty.
So many statuses are there.
You don't need all these statuses, right?
Mhm.
That's why I said for just for your
purpose.
You just have either accepted, cancelled,
declined, sent, right?
Mhm.
But if you have sent in this one,
there cannot be multiple sent,
there could be only one sent.
Similarly there can be only one accepted.
But there can be multiple declines within
within shipment, right within the options.
You cannot have multiple accepted,
multiple sent. You can have one accepted,
Yeah.
one sent, right?
But accepted and sent cannot be in the
Yeah.
same thing.
Yeah, of course.
Because yeah,
you send it and then they accept it.
So the send immediately gets replaced by
accepted or from send.
That is why you see here right from send
it can go to decline.
From send it can go to decline failed.
It can go to cancel right?
It can go to accept.
Right,
so so multiple transitions can can happen,
right?
And based on each of these transitions,
something else might happen.
OK.
That is why I'm saying it will be much
more complex for you, right?
You don't need all these,
you just keep accepted, cancel, declined,
sent.
Oh, instead of rejected,
I can call it canceled, right?
It is simple.
Cancel. Yeah, declined.
Rejected is say carrier. Yeah,
Or declined the second OK.
carrier that's not accepted it accepts it.
It'll call decline when the user. Yeah,
Declined, yeah.
user cancels the shipment itself.
So they will go and cancel the tender 1st
and then maybe cancel the shipment.
OK, perfect.
Oh, OK, uh, now.
OK, that is what I'm saying.
This is much more complex.
Hmm, it is a lot.
So I'm just giving you. Yeah, yeah, yeah,
I just see this is how it moves.
And there are different logics around it
for how it needs to move, right from hold.
Jesus Christ.
Yeah,
from hold it'll move from optimization,
then review. It can also go to approved.
Yeah, that is why I.
I'm saying this is much more complex.
So that is why I kept. Yeah,
OK.
just for because for the business users,
you know,
while while we are trying to tell them
the design,
it's easier to tell with one or two
statuses. They don't need to know.
They know it.
But for us to explain just one or two
statuses is enough because they're going
to see.
So now.
How they're going to use it right?
That is where when we write the stories,
we are going to put all these rules and
behind the scenes all these rules will
Um.
work.
Yeah, sure. And the stories are also for,
of course you have stories for the design
and development and everything.
Correct, correct. That will come later,
right?
Right now it is more about giving giving
them an idea of how it'll look like.
Uh huh.
OK, yeah, no problem. I I got you now.
I got you.
There was a confusion in in the in the
PowerPoint.
Hmm.
Yeah,
that is what this is all the tender
status you see here.
It says tender status, right?
It clearly says tender status.
These are all shipment status.
OK.
Right. So these are shipment status.
The tender status drives the shipment
status.
Right.
So something happens to the tender status.
Oh.
If it goes to accepted,
the shipment status moves to done, right?
That is why you see in the design here,
right?
Mhm.
It'll say OK, where did it go?
Maybe I opened this design see.
So shipment two, yeah, 2.
This is saying exceptions.
Jana, what is your background?
And did it go away?
What is my background?
What do you mean what I studied?
Yeah.
Yeah, what?
What is like your your specialty in in
your profession?
Am I?
My profession is right now is my is a
product manager.
Product manager specialized in domain.
Domain is logistics domain.
OK, but what background do you have?
You are an engineer. You are a.
Yeah, engineer. Yeah, I'm an engineer.
I studied mechanical, then manufacturing,
did my masters in manufacturing,
then worked in supply chain logistics.
Oh.
Then into IT.
Oh, that's very cool.
Yeah, so coming back here, what is this?
Yeah, not this one. This is the old one.
Yes, this is, this is.
This is why you like tools.
This is the old one.
OK.
This is the old design. No, no,
this is not a design.
This is a something that we did for
Odyssey.
OK.
Yeah, let me see. Where did I go?
Phase two QBR, Phase two Odyssey mock MVP.
Oh no, this is the one I opened. Yeah,
QBR.
Little complete management Cognizant.
Still shipments.
Not able to get the other one,
but if you share your screen I will be
able to tell you right? Yeah.
Yeah, I have. I have it here opened.
Um, I think it's this one.
What did you? What did you study?
Or mechatronics and then eutronics is
like robotics, something like that thing.
What is that?
Uh, mechatronics.
Uh, OK, OK.
So you are a mechanical electronics
And and then I.
Exactly.
And then I then I study graphics design
engineer and then you you're.
Uh.
like another, yeah.
OK, OK,
so you're now into graphic designing,
graphic and UX and all those things.
You have to go to the next PPT,
they're not this one, next one.
Oh, oh, OK.
This one, right?
Yeah, that's the one I was searching for.
Yeah, the next one,
the the other one with the tender view.
Oh, I got it. I switched it. Sorry.
Um.
That's not.
I think they are duplicates.
Give me a SEC. Oh, I see they're hiding.
They are hiding.
This is the no, this is the OK this one.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah. So if you go to the second screen,
right, 444444,
you see that tender actions,
whatever you saw there, right? Tender,
Mhm.
retender, cancel, decline, accepted,
right.
Yeah.
So you can do all the tender actions here,
whatever we.
All right, accepted, right?
You can make a shipment option accepted.
You can make an option declined.
That is why you need a checkbox to select
an option and to accept it.
OK.
Right.
You selection option and you can decline
it, right? Yeah, right.
You select an option and then you can
And you can.
decline it.
And then you can select multiple maybe.
Right.
Yeah, yeah, you can select.
We can give that option multiple.
We will think about the business rule
later,
but at the one time you can take only one
action, right? So yeah, you don't.
Only one, OK.
You don't normally take multiple actions
at a time. You take only one action.
Right. And when someone does this,
what happens is it is a shipment status.
OK.
OK, if you go back to sheet number one.
Oh, no, no, no. Go to the first sheet.
Sheet sheet. Yeah, go to the first,
second, third sheet. Yeah, stay here.
When third sheet. Third sheet.
Third sheet. Yeah. Yeah. If you stay here,
Oh, sorry.
where is the status of the shipment?
Did you not add the status of the
shipment?
Origin destination.
So probably we should add status of the
shipment here, right?
Somewhere we need to, you know,
in the grid, in the grid, grid, grid,
OK, in the first place.
I'm saying.
Grid.
We should have a yeah in the grid in the
Oh, indeed.
table we should have the status of the
shipment so you can show when it is
accepted it is done.
I showed you right how it changes between
shipment status.
Let me show you what I mean, right?
Let me share.
Yeah, I I I think, I think we have it,
Jana. It's here, actually.
That is it.
Actually the status.
You need to show the status in the
shipment, right?
Shipment. Yeah,
if you have a by shipment for every by
Uh, give.
shipment should have its own status.
Give me a second. I think it's here.
Oh, OK, by shipment. This is the number.
Yeah, by shipment number,
just look for status.
It should be there status.
I know that it is there,
but I don't know where I maybe it is not
part of the column here.
We have shipment status here. We have it,
so it's inside the.
Shipment status. Yeah,
that needs to be added there so that it
it shows that, say for example,
maybe here it is interchanged.
Uh.
Tender is not a right shipment status,
right? Done.
Done is a done is the shipment status and
tender status is going to be sent.
Oh.
OK, so this standard status could be sent.
Right. Accepted. No, no tender status.
Make it accepted,
accepted and then here it is going to be
shipment status is going to be done.
OK.
OK,
if you can list me the the the what
Right.
tender shipment status exists done and
I'm done maybe yeah please.
I I'll put it in the chat. Wait,
what are all the statuses like?
One second.
Give me the list of that and then tender
status we know already, I think, yeah.
I added it to the chat.
You can take a look at it.
Oh yeah, your screenshot. OK,
under status.
And when when it is accepted, right,
you see that there is an arrow mark that
is going accepted on the right side,
right? The tender status,
the box says on the top accepted.
Then it means that your shipment status
Yeah, accepted here.
should be done.
Oh, they are linked. Yeah, of course,
because this one drives this, OK.
Yeah, when it is canceled,
it should be review.
Um, when is declined should be reveal.
Right.
And then we have sent.
We just leave it like that, right?
For now, send like that.
Yeah, send. You can keep it as. Yeah,
you can just leave it as send. Yeah,
just show these three as of now, right?
For send,
OK.
your shipment status will be not review
anything. It'll be blank. That's it.
Blank OK.
Yeah,
because it's the the shipment is under
still under review, right? Not review,
it is processing something.
Then based on that it'll change.
Yeah.
And so and we have here approved late
part. I don't,
I shouldn't worry about this too, right.
Yeah, yeah, don't. Don't worry about that.
You can just,
you can just put done and review.
Yeah, for for you,
that is more than enough, yeah.
That's it. OK.
OK.
Then review and done is it and the
FedEx.
shipping status. OK, OK, I will,
I will advance on this and then I will
call you back I think.
Yeah, no problem. Yeah.
OK. Thank you. See you later. Bye-bye.
Sure. Thank you. Bye, bye. Yeah.